Episode 4
第 4 集
ma'am.
女士。
My aunt and uncle had a fight in the tea shop.
姑姑和叔叔在茶馆里吵架了。
How about this time?
这次怎么样？
Someone from my family came...
我家里有人来了...
And they said they were fighting...
他们还说他们正在打架……
At a tea shop because of a woman.
因为一个女人，在一家茶馆。
He told me to go and see it.
他叫我去看看。
Are you a girl again?
你又是个女孩了吗？
Why did they come to see me?
他们为什么来看我？
Where is my father?
我的父亲在哪里？
Your parents went to visit your grandparents.
你的父母去看望你的祖父母。
They can't go home.
他们不能回家。
So the assistant came to see the lady.
于是助理就来见这位女士。
so.
所以。
He must be out of control.
他一定是失控了。
You will die later. Let me tell you.
你稍后会死。 让我告诉你。
You will all die here.
你们都会死在这里。
Sir, my father has been sick for a long time.
先生，我父亲病了很长时间了。
He depends on the money I get here.
他依赖我在这里赚到的钱。
I can't keep up with you. I appeal.
我跟不上你了。 我上诉。
Let me go.
让我走。
I said. I'll take care of him...
我说。 我会照顾他的...
As long as you come back with me.
只要你跟我一起回来。
Is there anything else you want?
你还有什么想要的吗？
He tried to hide.
他试图隐藏。
Does he want that...
他想要这样吗……
Did he say he doesn't like you?
他有说不喜欢你吗？
good. you make me angry
好的。 你让我生气
Just wait and see.
拭目以待吧。
Brother, isn’t this enough?
兄弟，这还不够吗？
Dear sister, Qian.
亲爱的茜姐。
Good luck.
祝你好运。
Are you here to help my brother?
你是来帮助我兄弟的吗？
Those people are so ignorant...
这些人真是太无知了……
So how dare you hit my brother.
那你怎么敢打我弟弟。
Mr. Qian, how many people are you here with?
钱先生，您这里有多少人？
Do by that way!
就按这个方法做吧！
Why do you think I came to help you?
你以为我为什么来帮你？
How dare you ask your family for help...
你怎么敢向 你的家人寻求帮助......
While you're a thug?
当你是暴徒的时候？
Do you think this city belongs to your family?
你认为这座城市是你家人的吗？
you...
你...
You exaggerated the story.
你夸大了这个故事。
What makes you think...
是什么让你觉得...
I came to help him?
我是来帮他的？
We all heard him call you sister.
我们都 听到他叫你姐姐。
Mr. Zhong is a wise man.
钟先生是一位聪明人。
But he ruined his reputation...
但他却毁了他的名誉……
Because he can no longer control his family.
因为他已经无法控制自己的家人了。
Of course there are misunderstandings.
当然也有误会。
no way.
决不。
I'm just saying what I think.
我只是说我的想法。
Unfortunately Mr. Wise Zong...
可惜 宗贤先生……
Exchange fish eyes for pearls...
用鱼眼换珍珠……
And gets trapped by a woman.
还被女人困住了。
You me...
你我...
I've never seen it
我从来没见过
They Look like people passing by...
他们 看起来像是路过的人...
But they seem to know...
但他们似乎知道......
How I Married With Jong Ye-ran
我是如何结婚的 与钟艺兰结婚
Who is my brother looking for a knight with?
我的兄弟正在和谁一起寻找骑士？
- Police, be careful. - Who is that person?
- 警察，小心点。 - 那个人是谁？
that...
那...
who are you?
你是谁？
Have you lost your mind?
你疯了吗？
There are a lot of guards here.
这里有很多守卫。
I don't understand why they are needed...
我不明白为什么需要它们......
Servants helping them.
仆人帮助他们。
Guard, tie him up!
守卫，把他绑起来！
Who are you that binds me?
你是谁，束缚着我？
You slander the Zhong family.
你污蔑钟家。
Where are you!
你在哪里！
Tie him up too.
把他也绑起来。
Take it to court.
把它告上法庭。
Chief, did you make a mistake?
楼主，你是不是搞错了？
I showed it to my brother.
我把它拿给我哥哥看。
I was locked up in jail for a few days...
我被关在监狱里几天了...
It will help me correct my sister's mistake.
这将帮助我纠正姐姐的错误。
sibling...
兄弟...
How about you?
你呢？
I'm not a judge...
我不是法官...
So I cannot judge this case.
所以我无法判断这个案子。
But you keep making me angry.
但你却总是让我生气。
I also have an impatient personality.
我的性格也很急躁。
so...
所以...
Please explain to the judge...
请向法官解释...
together.
一起。
Kian.
基安.
What is your name?
你叫什么名字？
Longzhou...
龙州...
Jooyong, Bukan?
周勇、布坎？
Thank you for your kindness.
谢谢你的好意。
you look young
你看起来年轻
Don't forget to protect yourself ...
别忘了保护自己 ...
Before helping others.
在帮助别人之前。
Nothing is more important...
没有什么比这更重要了...
From yourself.
来自你自己。
The Zhong family will pay for your treatment.
钟家 会支付你的治疗费用。
It doesn't matter if you just follow the situation...
只要跟着情况走就没关系了...
Or leave a comment...
或者发表评论...
I know you did it to protect me ...
我知道你这么做是为了保护我 ...
Thank you for your kindness.
谢谢你的好意。
But you need to know...
但你需要知道...
Not everyone...
不是每个人...
I will do what I did for you
我会做我为你做的事
Kian. My brother was wrong.
基安. 我哥哥错了。
I will never do that again.
我再也不会这样做了。
I don't want to go to court.
我不想上法庭。
- Let go. - no. I don't want it.
- 松手。 - 不。我不想要它。
Wait a minute, ma'am.
等一下，女士。
I apologize on behalf of my brother...
我代表我的兄弟向你道歉……
Because I made you angry.
因为我让你生气了。
He is loud and clear...
他声音响亮、清晰……
So he is easily fooled.
所以他很容易被愚弄。
Don't let him influence you.
别让他影响你。
Don't apologize to me.
别向我道歉。
I don't want to interfere.
我不想干涉。
Just explain it to the judge.
向法官解释一下就可以了。
That's it.
就是这样。
We both apologize...
我们俩都道歉了...
And forget this.
忘记这一点。
This is just a fight.
这只是一场战斗。
We recommend not taking it to court.
我们建议不要将其告上法庭。
That's exactly right.
完全正确。
I think he has a point.
我认为他说得有道理。
You can just leave it alone.
你可以不管它。
But it's not your choice.
但这不是你的选择。
It depends on who is involved.
这取决于谁参与其中。
If Mr. Whoa, stop bothering me...
如果先生。哎呀，别再 烦我了……
I will forget it.
我会忘记它。
I won't put pressure on you.
我不会给你压力。
Absolutely not. Go, hurry.
绝对不。 走吧，快点。
Send my brother back...
送我弟弟回来...
And lock him up...
并把他关起来...
Before my parents return.
在我父母回来之前。
- Okay, ma'am. - Police, you...
- 好的，女士。 - 警察，你...
Teacher, please.
老师，请。
go away.
离开。
Who are they?
他们是谁？
Chenz!
陈兹！
Send someone to the tail to check...
派人到尾部查看……
Madam, I was really impressed.
女士，我真的很感动。
Tuan.
团。
I watched you from above.
我从上面看着你。
You are different...
你与众不同...
Because it is very strict.
因为它非常严格。
You are so kind.
你真好。
Women change after they get married.
女人结婚后就会发生变化。
Why didn’t our senior come with us?
为什么我们的前辈没有和我们一起来？
It's my family's thing.
这是我家人的事。
It would be better for that person not to come.
那个人还是不要来比较好。
so.
所以。
I've been out for a long time.
我已经出去很长时间了。
It's time to come back.
是时候回来了。
Can you send me back?
你能送我回去吗？
what?
什么？
My carriage is too small for two people.
我的马车对于两个人来说太小了。
If you don't like this cart ...
如果您不喜欢这款购物车 ...
please.
请。
Did you go out alone today?
今天你一个人出去吗？
afoot?
正在进行吗？
Don't panic.
不要惊慌。
Go ahead and try it. Didn't you say a word?
继续尝试。你没说一句话吗？
Is it Felic?
是费利克吗？
I am his sister-in-law.
我是他的嫂子。
Wouldn't it be rude to share my carriage ?
共用我的马车不是很不礼貌 吗？
What does he want?
他想要什么？
Sister-in-law.
嫂子。
Please forgive.
请原谅。
for what reason?
是什么原因？
Arrived at Jong Park.
到达钟公园。
Thank you for sending it , daughter-in-law.
谢谢你发来 ，儿媳妇。
He would later fall in love with Mu Yao.
后来他爱上了慕瑶。
What am I thinking?
我在想什么？
let's go.
我们走吧。
Have you seen those two men?
你见过那两个人吗？
no.
不。
They may be people passing through the city.
他们可能是这座城市的路过者。
It doesn't seem that way.
看来不是这样的。
Should we arrest them?
我们应该逮捕他们吗？
for what reason?
是什么原因？
They didn't do anything wrong today.
他们今天并没有做错什么。
Why are there so many People and things...
为什么有这么多 人和事......
Never seen this before?
以前从未见过这个？
Has my life changed...
我的生活改变了吗...
With a new choice?
有了新的选择？
But the important thing may not change
但重要的事情 可能不会改变
Want more food?
想要更多食物吗？
Assistant Lee...
李助理...
When do you worship ancestors ?
什么时候祭祖 ？
Two months left.
还剩下两个月。
Do you need anything?
你需要什么东西吗？
Muzula...
穆祖拉...
It's not too late...
现在还不算太晚...
So you can make plans
这样你就可以制定计划
Madam, Mr. Zhong has arrived.
女士，钟先生来了。
Tuan.
团。
I told them not to be too formal.
我告诉他们不要太正式。
Queen directly told me...
女王直接告诉我...
So as not to break the rules.
以免违反规则。
I just got back and I haven't had dinner yet.
我刚回来， 还没吃晚饭。
On time.
准时。
Why do you eat so little?
你为什么吃这么少？
I ate ...
我吃了 ...
before you come
在你来之前
Have I been ignoring you lately ?
我最近是不是不理你了 ？
Why don't you see me?
你为什么不见我？
About your brother's problem today?
关于你兄弟今天的问题？
You have to face...
你必须面对...
Lots of things to do every day.
每天都有很多事情要做。
I don't want to bother you...
我不想打扰你...
As long as I can manage it.
只要我能驾驭得了。
We are husband and wife.
我们是夫妻。
Why are you treating me like a stranger now ?
为什么现在 你却把我当陌生人一样对待？
The problem is that he is so stupid...
问题是他太傻了……
So that you can take care of yourself.
这样您就可以照顾好自己。
Or else people will think we are bullies.
不然别人 会认为我们是恶霸。
He listens to me.
他听我的。
So I can take care of myself.
这样我就能照顾好自己了。
Kian.
基安.
It looks cold...
看起来很冷...
Since we got married.
自从我们结婚以来。
You're overthinking it.
你想太多了。
Now we're married...
现在我们结婚了...
I must do my duty .
我必须尽我的职责 。
It's my fault...
我的错...
It's because I've been ignoring you since we got married.
因为自从我们结婚以来我就一直不理你。
I will treat you better.
我会对你 更好。
What about Muyao?
慕瑶呢？
How do you want to treat that person?
你想如何对待那个人？
I will take responsibility...
我会承担责任...
Because I married you.
因为我嫁给了你。
I didn't even ask.
我什至没有问。
What did you think at first...
一开始你是怎么想的...
Rather than making hasty decisions ?
而不是仓促做出决定 ？
Or maybe it's not fair to all of us.
或者也许这对我们所有人都不公平。
- Security... - It's late.
- 保安... - 已经晚了。
it's a good night.
这是一个美好的夜晚。
Tuan Zhong wants to spend the night here.
团忠想在这里过夜。
Why did you kick him out?
你为什么把他赶出去？
You know it too.
你也知道。
He thinks about other people.
他为别人着想。
The lady got married...
那位女士结婚了...
With him.
和他一起。
You can't make him think about you ...
你不能让他想你 ...
every time.
每次。
Being a wife and being a girl are different.
做妻子和 做女孩是不一样的。
You need to think carefully about the pros and cons...
你需要仔细考虑一下利弊...
Not your wife's feelings
不是你老婆的感受
I know what you're trying to say.
我知道你想说什么。
But I don't want to...
但我不想...
Make the same mistake
犯同样的错误
You are getting better at being a housekeeper.
你越来越擅长当管家了。
Thank you for accepting me, sir.
谢谢您接受我，先生。
How long do you want to stay here?
你想在这里呆多久？
Don't tell me you like being a maid.
别告诉我你喜欢当女仆。
Until I met the man who imprisoned my family.
直到我遇到了那个囚禁我家人的男人。
You are insisting on staying here...
你非要留在这里...
Just to investigate your family's case?
只是为了调查你家人的案子吗？
Qian doesn't want to get involved...
钱先生不想掺和...
In dispute.
在争吵。
you are a good friend
你是一个好朋友
Why can't I let him go?
为什么我不能放开他？
Did I say Hua Qian?
我有说华谦吗？
Who imprisoned my father?
谁囚禁了我的父亲？
You know better than anyone else...
你比谁都清楚...
And just fool yourself.
只是欺骗自己。
I'm not going to argue with you.
我 不会和你争论。
Qian is my wife.
钱是我老婆。
He is innocent.
他是无辜的。
Still, if you want to fight that person...
不过， 如果你想和那个人战斗的话……
I can't let you stay here any longer .
我不能再让你留在这里了 。
I took a risk...
我冒险了...
And welcome...
并欢迎...
Because of the past.
因为过去。
You can say anything now ...
现在 你可以说什么了...
To others when you leave.
离开时给别人。
I was scammed...
我被骗了...
With her innocence.
带着她的纯真。
Now I understand his true nature...
现在我明白了他的真实本质……
But sir, no.
但是先生，不。
For me...
为我...
Hua Qian was as cruel as a snake.
华千残忍如蛇。
- You... - Three months.
- 你... - 三个月。
If you can't prove it...
如果你不能证明...
My father was locked up for 3 months...
我父亲 被关了三个月……
I will leave Hwangcheong...
我要离开黄清了……
And it won't come back.
而且它不会回来。
I won't ruin it...
我不会毁掉它...
The teacher or that person.
老师或者那个人。
If you trust that person...
如果你信任那个人...
Why are you worried about my investigation?
你为什么担心我的调查？
I want to know too...
我也想知道...
I wonder if that person is trapping me...
不知道那个人是不是在坑我……
Or maybe I misunderstood.
或者也许我误解了。
I investigated.
我调查了。
No one in his family...
他家里没有人...
I'm involved in your case.
我参与了你的案子。
The person who filed the case has nothing to do with it...
提起诉讼的人 与此案无关......
With him and his family.
与他和他的家人在一起。
Of course, you don't know what he's talking about ...
当然，你不知道他在说什么 ......
Between me and that person.
我和那个人之间。
Even if I tell you , you won't believe me .
即使我告诉你，你也不会相信我。
I can't let him near me ...
我不能让他靠近我 ...
With this heart.
以此心。
I swear...
我发誓...
I just want to reveal it...
我只是想透露一下...
The truth about our family's case.
我们家案件的真相。
I don't want to lock him up.
我不想把他关起来。
If that person has nothing to do with this incident...
如果那个人与这件事无关的话……
I won't hurt him.
我不会伤害他。
If you break your promise...
如果你违背了你的承诺...
I will die and rot in hell.
我会死在地狱里腐烂。
great.
伟大的。
We give you 3 months.
我们给你3个月的时间。
The scent of this Qianhua perfume is...
这款千花香水的香味是……
It's different this time.
这次不同了。
It's freshly made...
是新鲜出炉的...
Same fresh Melur flowers.
同样新鲜的Melur花。
It's quite different from...
这与...完全不同
What we received.
我们收到了什么。
I will stop using this product now...
我现在将停止使用该产品...
If you don't like it.
如果你不喜欢它。
are you okay.
你还好吗。
How long have I been married?
我结婚多久了？
About a month.
大约一个月。
Time passes very slowly.
时间过得很慢。
Why is that so?
为什么会这样？
This month seems to pass quickly.
这个月似乎过得很快。
You won't understand.
你不会明白的。
When do you worship ancestors?
什么时候祭祖？
49 days left.
还剩 49 天。
This is the 24th time...
这已经是第24次了……
The lady asked me.
那位女士问我。
How slow.
多慢啊。
It's really slow.
真的很慢。
Why at this time Madam Madam - Is that so...
为什么这个时候 夫人夫人——是这样吗……
Want to attend the awards ceremony?
想参加颁奖典礼吗？
You always pretend to be sick...
你总是假装生病...
To avoid.
避免。
That's different.
那不一样。
This year's event is very important.
今年的活动非常重要。
This is their chance to express their love.
这 是他们表达爱意的机会。
But now...
但现在...
This is your only chance...
这是你唯一的机会...
Fix errors.
修正错误。
Express your love? WHO?
表达你的爱意？ WHO？
Secrets cannot be revealed.
秘密不能泄露。
You are worried about everything...
你 担心一切...
Except for the really important ones .
除了真正重要的 。
It's been a month since we got married.
我们结婚已经一个月了。
But you always sleep in the reading room.
但你 总是睡在阅览室。
When this comes out...
当这个出来的时候...
Sir, Nanfeng has arrived.
先生，南风来了。
Hello, madam.
你好女士。
What do you want this time?
这次你想要什么？
Madam, you told me to send it here.
女士， 您让我把它寄到这里。
What is he?
他是什么？
구친.
구친。
late.
晚的。
How about sleeping here?
睡在这里怎么样？
Did you tell me to leave?
你叫我离开吗？
I understand.
我明白。
After all, you're not coming back...
毕竟，你回不来了……
On the wedding night.
新婚之夜。
You left him alone to visit his family.
你让他一个人去探望他的家人。
Did you just learn how to speak?
你刚学会说话吗？
Sir, I didn't even ask.
先生，我什至没有问。
What did you think at first...
一开始你是怎么想的...
Rather than making hasty decisions ?
而不是仓促做出决定 ？
Or maybe it's not fair to all of us.
或者也许这对我们所有人都不公平。
Please let me know. How can I make up for my mistakes with that person?
请告诉我。 我该如何弥补对那个人的错误呢？
Finally you realize.
终于你意识到了。
easy.
简单的。
You are a good girl.
你是个好女孩。
Teacher, can you...
老师，你能...
Knowing his hobbies.
了解他的爱好。
His hobby strategy...
他的爱好策略...
This Guqin was made by the best craftsmen...
这把古琴 是由最好的工匠制作的......
Zhang Jing.
张静.
It's the only one in the world.
这是世界上唯一的一个。
You are famous for your Guqin skills.
您因古琴技艺而闻名。
I was looking for it to give as a gift to my aunt...
我一直在寻找它作为礼物送给我的阿姨......
Because you can use it well .
因为你可以很好地利用它 。
Thank you to him.
谢谢他。
Yinxing, simpan dalam stor.
Yinxing, simpan dalam stor.
Don't you want to play?
你不想玩吗？
I'll try it next time.
下次我会尝试一下。
I go first.
我先走了。
You were originally really excited...
原来你真的很兴奋……
When I saw the great Guchin.
当我看到伟大的古钦时。
It seems...
它似乎...
The lady is not interested at all.
这位女士根本不感兴趣。
I noticed...
我注意到...
You don’t like Nanfeng.
你不喜欢南风。
Because he always brings bad news.
因为他总是带来坏消息。
One wedding night long ago...
很久以前的一个新婚之夜...
And when I come home during the day ...
当我白天 回家时...
Qianzhi, that’s nonsense.
千之，这是胡说八道。
I think he's a good person.
我认为他是一个好人。
ma'am...
女士...
This board is made from premium Torreya wood.
该板 由优质香榧木制成。
Both pieces and boxes...
不论是单片还是盒子...
Made of natural jade.
由天然玉石制成。
I was looking for it to give as a gift to my aunt...
我一直在寻找它作为礼物送给我的阿姨......
Because you can use it well .
因为你可以很好地利用它 。
Madam, you work hard...
姐，你辛苦了……
Look for this bristle brush.
寻找这款猪鬃刷。
Your writing is beautiful...
你的文笔真美……
And I will use it well.
而且我会好好利用它。
This is the best paper and inkstone in town.
这 是城里最好的纸和砚台。
Ma'am, you can use...
女士，您可以用...
draw.
画。
Keep it in store.
将其保存起来。
Madam, you treated me well .
夫人，您对我很好 。
He knows you have a talent for literature...
他知道你有文学天赋...
And prepare for this.
并为此做好准备。
Just save it to storage.
只需将其保存到存储中即可。
He keeps everything I send?
他保留了我发送的所有内容？
- yes. - You didn't even touch it?
- 是的。 - 你连碰都没碰过吗？
of.
的。
He said he would calm down...
他说他会冷静下来...
If I knew that person's hobbies.
如果我知道那个人的爱好就好了。
perhaps...
也许...
You acted too late.
你行动太晚了。
yes. Now that I think about it, it's been a month...
是的。 现在想想，一个月过去了……
After the wedding is over.
婚礼结束后。
Maybe he should meet you...
也许他应该见见你...
And not this gift.
而不是这份礼物。
Somehow...
不知何故...
I would like your advice.
我想听听你的建议。
Did you bring anything?
你带东西了吗？
- not needed. - Please bring something.
- 不需要。 - 请带点东西来。
Please bring something, sir.
请带点东西来，先生。
I remember you liked sweet foods .
我记得你喜欢吃甜食 。
So I brought dessert.
所以我带了甜点。
He suffered from toothache before marriage.
婚前他患有牙痛。
The doctor said I shouldn't eat it...
医生说不能吃...
Another dessert.
另一个甜点。
The teacher is very kind.
老师很和蔼。
Now let's put it on the table.
现在让我们把它放在桌子上。
No problem...
没问题...
Until I got here?
直到我到达这里？
You don't like...
你不喜欢...
That gift?
那个礼物？
Of course I like it.
我当然喜欢。
So what...
所以呢...
Today's workshop inspection has been cancelled.
今天的车间检查已取消。
Is there a place you want to go?
有你想去的地方吗？
Work is more important.
工作更重要。
You need to take care...
你需要照顾...
First off, it's official.
首先，这是官方的。
You always live in this house.
你总是住在这所房子里。
I'm afraid you might be bored.
恐怕你会觉得无聊。
no.
不。
I always go out when I have time.
当我有时间的时候我总是出去。
So where are you going today?
那么你今天要去哪里？
I will follow you.
我会跟随你。
are you okay.
你还好吗。
what?
什么？
Are there places I can't go?
有我不能去的地方吗？
Taman species
塔曼物种
Master, your wife has arrived.
主人，您的夫人来了。
Please forgive me, master.
请原谅我，主人。
Why did you visit me?
你为什么来看我？
Did something happen between you and Yellen?
你和耶伦之间发生了什么事情吗？
long time no see...
好久不见...
and i miss you so much
我非常想念你
So I came to see my master.
于是我就来见我的师父。
sit down.
坐下。
Yes, master.
是的主人。
Master, the prince has arrived.
主人，王子来了。
Goodbye, mother.
再见，妈妈。
Permit. Please sit here.
允许。 请坐在这里。
You called the doctor yesterday.
你昨天打电话给医生了。
Are you feeling unwell?
你感觉不舒服吗？
naught.
什么也没有。
Your child has indigestion.
你的孩子有消化不良。
Take care of your health.
照顾你的健康。
As a teacher...
作为一名老师...
You should...
你应该...
Eat dessert in moderation.
适量吃甜点。
N.Gao...
高恩...
Have you ever worked?
你工作过吗？
At the palace before you came here with me.
在你和我一起来这里之前，在宫殿里。
You don't need me...
你不需要我...
You're just trying to remind me, right?
你只是想提醒我，对吧？
Yes, master.
是的主人。
My son understands, mother.
我儿子明白，妈妈。
Monarch...
君主...
Yaxiang has something to report.
亚翔有事要报告。
Please forgive me, master.
请原谅我，主人。
What is that?
那是什么？
Spices sent by a comprador...
买办送来的香料……
We already broke up.
我们已经分手了。
This is available stock.
这是可用库存。
I remember reporting it...
我记得举报过...
This was yesterday.
这是昨天的事了。
Why did you come back here with inventory?
你为什么带着库存回来？
furthermore...
此外...
Strong winds these past few days...
这几天风很大...
Damage flowers in your yard.
损坏院子里的花朵。
How about we buy flowers?
我们去买花怎么样？
Are they of the same species again?
它们又是同一物种吗？
You can ask your assistant about this minor issue .
这个小问题你可以向你的助理询问 。
If you don't have anything important to do, leave.
如果你没有什么重要的事情要做，那就离开吧。
Yes, master.
是的主人。
Mom site...
妈妈网站...
Be energetic every time you come.
每次来都充满活力。
Master, Mr. Hwaman has arrived.
师父，华曼先生来了。
These days, I rarely visit my grandmother .
这些天，我很少去看望奶奶了 。
So mom sent someone this morning...
所以 今天早上妈妈就派人来了...
I'm going to invite that person...
我要去邀请那个人...
So that mom can talk to that person .
这样妈妈就可以和那个人说话了 。
Because you are here...
因为你在这里...
Mom will tell him to go.
妈妈会叫他走。
He is here. Please let him in.
他来了，请让他进来。
Let him in.
让他进来。
Yes, master.
是的主人。
Why are you so stubborn?
你为什么这么固执？
Nampak?
南帕克？
His father gave him up
他的父亲放弃了他
Otherwise He wouldn't act strange...
否则 他不会表现得奇怪......
It looks weak
看起来很弱
Please forgive me, master.
请原谅我，主人。
Aren't you my aunt's cousin?
你不是我姨妈的表弟吗？
However, the two are rarely seen together.
不过， 两人很少在一起。
He lived with his aunt in the city.
他和他的姨妈住在城里。
We only visit each other during festivals .
我们只在节日期间互相拜访 。
Now he...
现在他...
master's maid
主人的女仆
I can't bother him at will.
我不能随意打扰他。
Qian, it feels awkward to say that.
钱，说起来感觉很尴尬。
Why don't you look friendly with your cousin?
你为什么对你表弟看起来不友善？
ma'am?
女士？
Where are you?
你在哪里？
We are still family...
我们还是一家人...
Even if we stretch.
即使我们伸展。
Oh, yes, you can say it...
哦，是的，你可以这么说...
If you need anything...
如果你需要什么...
Di Taman species.
迪塔曼种。
We will do our best to help you...
我们将尽力 帮助您...
if i need it
如果我需要的话
Madam, he is just Assistant Qi's son...
夫人， 他只是齐助理的儿子……
A person who works at a jongbak.
在钟博工作的人。
But it looks like he already lives there.
但看起来他已经住在那里了。
He is very rude.
他很粗鲁。
Don't look for things with him.
不要和他一起找东西。
One of those women...
其中一位女士...
Maybe you will be a lady here someday.
也许有一天你会成为这里的一位女士。
Stupid girl.
愚蠢的女孩。
That person...
那个人...
Save these women...
拯救这些女人...
Just because he's bored?
就因为他无聊？
Madam, you are very brave...
小姐，你真是勇敢啊……
They say it has something to do with Hua Man...
据说和花曼有关系……
Before your majesty and your lord.
在陛下和陛下面前。
That's smart.
这很聪明。
look. thurible.
看。 易熔的。
- Show me this. - good.
- 给我看看这个。 - 好的。
Are you tired?
你累了吗？
Absolutely.
绝对地。
You should cover your mouth when you laugh...
笑的时候一定要捂住嘴
In front of my master.
在我师父面前。
Why did you decide...
你为什么决定...
Do you want to go to Bell Park today?
你今天想去贝尔公园吗？
It's rare for you to be kind to your aunt...
你对阿姨这么好真是难得啊……
And I want to spend time with you.
我想和你共度时光。
I want to be with him.
我想和他在一起。
why?
为什么？
He is from the palace.
他是皇宫里的人。
He is thoughtful.
他很体贴。
If you do not mind...
如果你不介意的话...
I can have his heart.
我可以得到他的心。
I thought about it.
我想过这个问题。
Royal Princess Site...
皇家公主遗址...
The only place you can't go with me.
唯一一个你不能和我一起去的地方。
Ah, that's it! What are you saying, ma'am?
啊，就是这样！ 女士，你在说什么？
Let go of the reins...
松开缰绳...
Just to hug that person better?
只是为了更好地拥抱那个人 吗？
You are very smart.
你很聪明。
He will miss you even more now.
他 现在会更加想念你。
Nanfeng should have told me...
南风应该告诉我的……
Before we go...
在我们走之前...
I'm taking a break for a month and a half...
我要休息半个月了
To spend more time with you.
为了和你一起度过更多的时间。
halfmoon?
半月？
Monarch
君主
The wife has arrived.
妻子已经到了。
Please forgive me, master.
请原谅我，主人。
Sir, your wife is coming.
先生，您的妻子来了。
Monarch
君主
The lady came again.
老太太又来了。
Please forgive me, master.
请原谅我，主人。
Master, how are you?
师父，你好吗？
Sir, your wife is here.
先生，您的妻子来了。
- Master...
- 师父...
I have come to see my master again.
我又来看我的师父了。
What do you want to do?
你想让我做什么？
Let me help you.
我来帮你。
Tuan.
团。
Sir, your wife is here again.
先生，您的妻子又来了。
Once more?
再一次？
Dwan Handover
Dwan交接
Teacher, this bead was made...
老师，这颗珠子是做出来的……
From the scent...
从气味中...
It was consecrated by an old monk.
它是由一位老和尚开光的。
do you like it?
你喜欢它？
You are good.
你很好。
What happened ma'am...
夫人怎么了……
During these two weeks?
这两周期间？
Why do you come here every day?
你为什么每天都来这里？
You always say that, master...
老师您总是这么说……
Treat him like your own child from the time he is young.
从小就把他当作自己的孩子一样对待。
He is busy now.
他现在很忙。
It is my duty to spend time with my master...
和主人一起度过时光是我的责任……
For his part.
就他而言。
nice couple.
很般配。
You make us all jealous.
你让我们都嫉妒。
Yellen has been very busy these days.
耶伦这几天很忙。
Beta will tell him...
贝塔会告诉他……
Care...
关心...
About his family.
关于他的家人。
He should pay more attention to his career.
他应该更加关注自己的事业。
Don't worry, master.
别担心，主人。
I'm serious?
我是认真的？
Absolutely.
绝对地。
Don't tell him to do something else.
不要告诉他做其他事情。
Your Majesty, the Queen commands the people...
陛下，女王 命令人民……
This lich was sent from the south.
这个巫妖是从南方派来的。
Of course it takes time and energy, but...
当然，这需要时间和精力，但是……
To send this lich...
为了送这个巫妖...
This season.
这一季。
Her Majesty loves my lord very much.
太后陛下 非常爱我的主子。
It's not beta.
这不是测试版。
His grandson loves Richie.
他的孙子很喜欢里奇。
Send it to Siwoo.
发送给思宇。
Yes, master.
是的主人。
Su Wuniang seems to be busy.
苏五娘似乎很忙。
I'm free now.
我现在有空。
I can take it.
我可以接受。
You take advantage of every opportunity you have.
你会充分利用你所拥有的每一个机会。
How dare you accept a compliment...
怎么敢接受别人的夸奖……
At my lord's suggestion?
是按照大人的建议吗？
Teacher Qi, I miss your misunderstanding.
齐老师，我很怀念你的误会。
I just want to help my master.
我只是想帮助我的主人。
Larger residences...
较大的住宅...
More tricks.
更多技巧。
Now you are free.
现在你自由了。
What do you mean, send me this lich?
把这个巫妖送给我是什么意思？
me?
我？
This is a smart move.
这是一个明智的举动。
Your Majesty is accustomed to palace life.
陛下习惯了宫廷生活。
With just one action, His Majesty resolved their conflict.
国王陛下 仅用一个动作就解决了他们的冲突。
Follow my orders, my lord.
遵照我的命令，大人。
Tuan.
团。
Your Majesty has instructed...
陛下已指示...
To get the lychee.
去摘荔枝。
Do you know how to read a ledger?
你知道如何阅读账本吗？
Look at this ledger.
看看这个账本。
Cash payment details are being recorded.
正在记录现金付款详细信息。
What did your brother do...
你弟弟做了什么...
At the store in your father's name.
在你父亲名下的商店里。
Do you think your father knows?
你认为你父亲知道吗？
I also heard another assistant say:
我还听到另一位助理说：
Your brother always spends a lot of money...
你弟弟总是 花很多钱...
In a brothel.
妓院里。
Didn't your father really teach him?
你父亲真的没有教过他吗？
Or did your father do the same?
或者你的父亲 也这样做过吗？
Teacher, my younger brother liked to show off from a young age.
老师，我弟弟 从小就喜欢炫耀。
My father is busy working at the store.
我父亲在店里忙着工作。
So I couldn't educate my younger brother well...
所以没能好好教育弟弟……
And let him escape.
并让他逃走。
How do you feel?
你感觉如何？
Should we punish him for his actions ?
我们应该为他的行为惩罚他吗 ？
Shen is my younger brother.
沉是我弟弟。
He is my family.
他是我的家人。
Even though he made a lot of mistakes...
尽管他 犯了很多错误...
I don't know how to punish that person ...
我不知道该怎么惩罚这个人 ...
Because he is old...
因为他老了……
And I'm just a girl.
而我只是一个女孩。
You are smart and know how.
你很聪明并且知道如何做。
I shouldn't make suggestions.
我不应该提出建议。
Hua's assistant always brags...
华助理总是吹牛……
That daughter is perfect.
那个女儿真是完美啊。
Why are you stuck in front of me?
你为什么挡在我面前？
Your parents might consider...
你的父母可能会考虑...
Their kids are the best.
他们的孩子是最棒的。
Exaggeration is inevitable.
夸张是不可避免的。
Lakaman Bonus
拉卡曼奖金
You are back.
你回来了。
He asked about the owner earlier.
他之前询问过店主的情况。
I went out quietly.
我悄悄出去了。
You caught me again.
你又抓住了我。
Please keep this a secret from me.
请对我保密。
Are you going to buy dessert for your mom?
你要给你妈妈买甜点吗？
That's the only reason...
这是唯一的原因...
Let me wander.
让我去流浪吧
Why did you go out alone?
你为什么一个人出去？
You need to bring a security guard.
你需要带一名保安。
I have a security guard.
我有一个保安。
They are hiding.
他们正在躲藏。
I won't be free...
我不会自由...
If I am with a group of security guards .
如果我和一群保安在一起。
OK. I will return first.
好的。 我先回来。
See you again, seniors.
又见面了，前辈们。
difference.
不同之处。
Your new wife has changed a lot.
你的新妻子改变了很多。
I met him today.
我今天遇见了他。
He now reminds me of his father.
他 现在让我想起了他的父亲。